One of the most common types of unit tests is
to test a function to see if it performs as it
should. For us to test a function correctly,
we need to know what results we expect to see
when testing said function. For this example,
I will use the function we built elsewhere in
the course to run some tests. Testing a function
involves anticipating known results and testing
the function to see if the expected results
are returned. In this 532-functions file,
we have a function defined on line 2 that
has two arguments: score and multiplier.
The function is used to calculate a game
player’s total score. Line 3 returns the
score multiplied by the multiplier. On lines
5 and 6, we have two tests for this function,
and to the right of each test is a comment
with an expected value. I will run this code,
and we see the two expected values. If the
tests did not work, we would need to look
either at the data being used to test the function
or the logic of the function itself. Functions,
like all other code, should be tested before
an app is put in production, as having
incorrect function results can lead to financial,
statistical, and credibility issues within an app.